PERSONAL DETAILS

- Name
 Ramiz Hida
- Address

 Bayern
- Phone number+49 151 62662060
- Email ramizhida00@gmail.com
- LinkedIn
 https://www.linkedin.com/in
 /ramiz-hida/
- □ Website
 https://ramizhida.github.io/p
 ortfolio-website/

GITHUB

https://github.com/RamizHida/

WEB DEVELOPMENT SKILLS

FRONTEND

React.JS ES5 & ES6 JavaScript HTML5

CSS / SASS

Bootstrap

Test Driven Development (unittesting with Jest and integrationtesting with Cucumber) Responsive Web Design

BACKEND

Node.js
Express
RESTful APIs
Non-relational databases
(MongoDB)
Relational databases
(PostgreSQL)

TOOLS

Version control (git)
Github
Postman
Command Line Interface (CLI)
Microsoft Excel

RAMIZ HIDA

Certified Full Stack Web Developer that creates responsive, user-oriented web applications. Experience ranging from the production of data visualizations for better understanding of customer needs in the energy industry, to the creation of both frontend and backend applications using tools such as React JS, Node, and noSQL databases, among others.



MY WEB PROJECTS

Meet App Oct - Nov 2023, Bayern DE

- Developed a Progressive Web Application (PWA) that was programmed with React following a test-driven and behavior-driven approach.
- · Integrated a serverless backend with AWS lambda for authentication and authorization of users.
- Implemented unit function testing with Jest and end-to-end testing with Puppeteer resulting in a fullytested web application which allows its users to filter for events using the Google Calendar API.

MyFlix Movie App Sep - Oct 2023, Bayern DE

- Created a Single Page Application (SPA) with a client-side and server-side from scratch.
- Built a RESTful API with Node JS and Express, that communicates with a non-relational database (MongoDB) to store user data.
- Developed a responsive web application with React, that supports CRUD functionality and incorporates API testing with Postman, resulting in a user-friendly interface which allows its users to signup, browse different movies, and update their user info.



WORK EXPERIENCE

2021 - 2022

Natural Gas Technician

Southern Company, Gwinnett County, USA

- Helped increase daily service goals by 3% by developing data visualizations charts using Tableau, which helped depict the number of our future customer base.
- Increased customer satisfaction through the recording of newly constructed gas meters using documentation software.

2019 - 2021

Retail Associate

Target, Georgia, United States

2014 - 2018

Sales Associate

Sam's Club, Snellville, GA, USA

- Increased membership sales by 94% by offering a special discount during the busiest time of the year.
- Provided outstanding customer services to more than 400 members weekly, increasing membership count from previous year .
- Streamlined frontend operations through reorganizing the warehouse floor.



EDUCATION

Jun 2023 - Dec 2023

Certified Full Stack Web Developer

Career Foundry

Aug 2014 - May 2019

Bachelor of Science

Georgia Gwinnett College, Georgia, United States